<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Good Thoughts on Jeff&#39;s Overlook</title>
    <link>/good_thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Good Thoughts on Jeff&#39;s Overlook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/good_thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry</title>
      <link>/good_thoughts/poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/good_thoughts/poetry/</guid>
      <description>Nothing Gold Can Stay  Nature’s first green is gold,
Her hardest hue to hold,
Her early leaf’s a flower;
But only so an hour.
Then leaf subsides to leaf.
So Eden sank to grief,
So dawn goes down to day.
Nothing gold can stay.
- Robert Frost
  The Road Not Taken  Two roads diverged in a yellow wood,
And sorry I could not travel both,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Excerpts</title>
      <link>/good_thoughts/text-excerpts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/good_thoughts/text-excerpts/</guid>
      <description>Insert Lead paragraph here.
A augue nunc lacus auctor efficitur tempor placerat, dictum volutpat mi vitae viverra porta non sem, himenaeos senectus vivamus potenti cubilia sollicitudin. Curae cursus inceptos tincidunt magna mi nibh ad enim etiam, molestie eu quis primis hendrerit taciti phasellus. Feugiat ultricies dictumst iaculis potenti odio laoreet urna at, ultrices curae leo accumsan proin sem lobortis.
Heading 2 Sollicitudin ornare odio blandit aenean enim lacus accumsan elementum vestibulum porta mauris lorem, ullamcorper class fermentum sem hendrerit ante augue penatibus scelerisque felis leo proin,ad nascetur venenatis sodales dignissim viverra suspendisse turpis convallis condimentum sapien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Media</title>
      <link>/good_thoughts/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/good_thoughts/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Movies
Good Will Hunting  Real loss is only possible when you love something more than you love yourself.
- Sean
  Rocky Balboa  The world ain’t all sunshine and rainbows. It’s a very mean and nasty place, and I don’t care how tough you are, it will beat you to your knees and keep you there permanently if you let it. You, me, or nobody is gonna hit as hard as life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual</title>
      <link>/good_thoughts/spiritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/good_thoughts/spiritual/</guid>
      <description>Nothing is more practical than finding God,
than falling in Love ina quite absolute, final way.
What you are in love with,
what seizes your imagination, will affect everything.
It will decide
what will get you out of bed in the morning,
what you do with your evenings,
how you spend your weekends,
what you read, whom you know,
what breaks your heart,
and what amazes you with joy and gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>