<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on Jeff Cavanagh</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on Jeff Cavanagh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimzing World Electrical Cost</title>
      <link>/projects/minimzing-world-electrical-cost-graduate-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/minimzing-world-electrical-cost-graduate-project/</guid>
      <description>Indirect Costs of the Various Energy Sources Coast Coefficients by Fuel Source (Production, Import, Export, Consumption) Packages Used to Build Model Upper Limit on Fuel Sources Defining Constraints Energy Production Capacity by Nation Defining the Objective Function Putting the Constraints Together Solving the Problem   For my graduate project I created an optimization model that analyzes the cost of electricity world wide and determines how expensive the indirect costs of fossil fuel consumption need to be in order for the installation of renewable electricity sources to be a more financially viable alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPRINT 8</title>
      <link>/fitness/sprint-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fitness/sprint-8/</guid>
      <description>What is SPRINT 8?? Issues with Traditional Cardio and Dieting  Long Duration, Slow, Steady State Cardio Dieting for Weight Loss (Heavy Caloric Restriction)  Critical Components of any Training Program  How SPRINT 8 Uses this Information  Sprint Intensity vs. Steady State Cardio SPRINT 8 Benchmarks Benefits  Short Term Long Term  How to do It!  Format Exercise Selection Nutrition Other Considerations    SPRINT 8 is a sprint style, interval-based cardio workout created by Coach Phil Campbell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in R</title>
      <link>/analytics/machine-learning-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analytics/machine-learning-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Supervised vs. Unsupervised Learning Supervised Learning  Tree Based Methods  Decision Trees Bagging/Random Forest Boosting  Generalized Additive Models Support Vector Machines Natural Language Processing  Unsupervised Learning  Clustering Dimensionality Reduction  Principal Component Analysis   Summary  Pros and Cons of Decision Trees    Machine learning is a broad and ever evolving topic and any good data scientist needs to have a strong grasp of the major techniques to know when to use which method and how best to apply them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy</title>
      <link>/perspective/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>To become empty is to become one with the divine; this is the Way.
- Awa Kenzo
  Work done for a reward is much lower than work done in the Yoga of wisdom. Set thy heart upon thy work, but never on its reward. Work not for reward, but never cease to do thy work.
- The Bhagavad Gita
  Very few go astray who comport themselves with restraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appetizers/Sides</title>
      <link>/recipes/appetizers-sides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/appetizers-sides/</guid>
      <description>   Bacon, Jalapeno, &amp;amp; Garlic Green Beans Guacamole Honey Vinegar Dressing Loaded Sweet Potato   Bacon, Jalapeno, &amp;amp; Garlic Green Beans  Guacamole  Honey Vinegar Dressing  Loaded Sweet Potato  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Football Food</title>
      <link>/recipes/football-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/football-food/</guid>
      <description>   GameDay Potato Nachos Guacamole Loaded Sweet Potato   GameDay Potato Nachos  Guacamole  Loaded Sweet Potato  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat</title>
      <link>/recipes/meat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/meat/</guid>
      <description>   Beef  GameDay Potato Nachos Ginger Beef and Broccoli Rump Roast  Chicken  Chicken &amp;amp; Quinoa Tortilla Soup Grilled Chicken Caesar Salad Honey Hot Chicken Italian Balsamic Grilled Chicken Pineapple Pepper Chicken  Pork  Chile Pork Chops with Pineapple Pork Chop Saltimbocca  Turkey  Moroccan White Bean Chili Pirate Stew Turkey Quinoa Taco Skillet    Beef GameDay Potato Nachos  Ginger Beef and Broccoli  Rump Roast   Chicken Chicken &amp;amp; Quinoa Tortilla Soup  Grilled Chicken Caesar Salad  Honey Hot Chicken  Italian Balsamic Grilled Chicken  Pineapple Pepper Chicken   Pork Chile Pork Chops with Pineapple  Pork Chop Saltimbocca   Turkey Moroccan White Bean Chili  Pirate Stew  Turkey Quinoa Taco Skillet   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Jeff</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>** Welcome to my Site! **
My name is Jeff and I am a data scientist living in Boston, MA. I created this website as an outlet for my work, interests, and outlook on life.
I believe that the potential for growth and improvement (in virtually anything) is limitless and that there is no problem without a solution. This website is a manifestation of those beliefs that showcases my abilities, passions, and influences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalities</title>
      <link>/perspective/personalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/personalities/</guid>
      <description>Strength does not come from winning. Your struggles develop your strengths. When you go through hardships and decide not to surrender, that is strength.
- Arnold Schwarzenegger
  For me life is about continuously being hungry. The meaning of life is not simply to exist, to survive, but to move ahead, to group, to achieve, to conquer.
- Arnold Schwarzenegger
  Impossible is just a big word thrown around by small men who find it easier to live in the world they’ve been given than to explore the power they have to change it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast</title>
      <link>/recipes/breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/recipes/breakfast/</guid>
      <description>   Berry Oatmeal Bake Fried Rice Lembas Bread (Power Bar) Lemon-Blueberry-Banana Pancakes Quinoa Breakfast Bowl   Berry Oatmeal Bake  Fried Rice  Lembas Bread (Power Bar)  Lemon-Blueberry-Banana Pancakes  Quinoa Breakfast Bowl  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry</title>
      <link>/perspective/poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/poetry/</guid>
      <description>Nothing Gold Can Stay The Road Not Taken   Nothing Gold Can Stay  Nature’s first green is gold,
Her hardest hue to hold,
Her early leaf’s a flower;
But only so an hour.
Then leaf subsides to leaf.
So Eden sank to grief,
So dawn goes down to day.
Nothing gold can stay.
- Robert Frost
  The Road Not Taken  Two roads diverged in a yellow wood,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Text Data</title>
      <link>/analytics/processing-text-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analytics/processing-text-data/</guid>
      <description>Setup Transforming Raw Text into Data Frame Text Analysis  Counts Document Frequencies    Text data cannot be processed identically to numerical or categorical data. Is there a way then to analyze text data and obtain insight from it??
Of course! All it takes is an adapted approach and a little more work upfront.
Quite a bit of potential data is unstructured and textual in nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Excerpts</title>
      <link>/perspective/text-excerpts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/text-excerpts/</guid>
      <description>Just Mercy   Just Mercy  We are all broken by something. We have all hurt someone and have been hurt. We all share the condition of brokenness even if our brokenness is not equivalent…
…Thomas Merton said: We are bodies of broken bones. I guess I’d always known but never fully considered that being broken is what makes us human. We all have our reasons. Sometimes we’re fractured by the choices we make; sometimes we’re shattered by things we would never have chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping</title>
      <link>/analytics/web-scrape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analytics/web-scrape/</guid>
      <description>Setup  CSS Tool Data  rvest Selenium   Unfortunately, not all data is contained within neat data frames. There is a virtually unlimited amount of data contained within web pages, but extracting and manipulated that information into a usable and familiar format is a major obstacle. This post will serve as an introduction on how to extract data from web pages using R and Python with the packages rvest and Selenium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test_homepage</title>
      <link>/posts/test-homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/test-homepage/</guid>
      <description>This is a test</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movies</title>
      <link>/perspective/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Good Will Hunting Hitch Lion King The Replacements Rocky Balboa Creed   Good Will Hunting  Real loss is only possible when you love something more than you love yourself.
- Sean Maguire
  You’ll have bad times, but it’ll always wake you up to the good stuff you weren’t paying attention to. - Sean Maguire
  Hitch  Never lie, steal, cheat, or drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual</title>
      <link>/perspective/spiritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/spiritual/</guid>
      <description>Nothing is more practical than finding God,
than falling in Love in a quite absolute, final way.
What you are in love with,
what seizes your imagination, will affect everything.
It will decide
what will get you out of bed in the morning,
what you do with your evenings,
how you spend your weekends,
what you read, whom you know,
what breaks your heart,
and what amazes you with joy and gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual</title>
      <link>/posts/spiritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/spiritual/</guid>
      <description>Nothing is more practical than finding God,
than falling in Love ina quite absolute, final way.
What you are in love with,
what seizes your imagination, will affect everything.
It will decide
what will get you out of bed in the morning,
what you do with your evenings,
how you spend your weekends,
what you read, whom you know,
what breaks your heart,
and what amazes you with joy and gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endgame</title>
      <link>/fitness/endgame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fitness/endgame/</guid>
      <description>Week 1  Monday: Compound Lower Body Tuesday: Compound Upper Body Wednesday: Sprint/Core Thursday: Uni-Lateral Lower Body Friday: Uni-Lateral Upper Body Saturday: Multifunctional  Week 2  Monday: Compound Lower Body Tuesday: Compound Upper Body Wednesday: Sprint/Core Thursday: Uni-Lateral Lower Body Friday: Uni-Lateral Upper Body Saturday: Multifunctional  Complex Options   I put this workout together in the summer of 2019. At its core it is an upper/lower split.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Trail Analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/hiking-trail-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/hiking-trail-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Setup Partitioning the Data Interaction of Predictor Variables Model Building  Linear Regression LDA QDA Logistic Regression KNN  Cross Validation Tree-Based Methods  Bagging Random Forest GBM Classification Predictions    The following was my final project for a Predictive Analytics course. It analyzed data on hiking trails throughout the US and created and compared models predicting whether or not a given trail will be rated above 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Modeling Starter Kit</title>
      <link>/analytics/methods-of-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analytics/methods-of-regression/</guid>
      <description>Setup Regression Models  Simple Linear Regression Multiple Linear Regression  Classification models  Logistic Regression Linear Discriminant Analysis (LDA) Quadratic Discriminant Analysis (QDA) K-Nearest Neighbors (KNN)  Cross-Validation   This post will cover some basic methods of regression analysis and how to apply them in R. It will also serve as a warm-up for the posts that explore more advanced machine learning and AI methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL Team Wins Regression Analysis</title>
      <link>/posts/nfl-team-wins-regression-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/nfl-team-wins-regression-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This was a final project I completed for my Regression and Time Series Analysis Course. I took data from the 2017 NFL season and used it to see what metrics were significant in predicting the number of wins a team would achieve.
Here is the write up of the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL Team Wins Regression Analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/nfl-team-wins-regression-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nfl-team-wins-regression-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This was a final project I completed for my Regression and Time Series Analysis Course. I took data from the 2017 NFL season and used SPSS to determine what metrics were significant in predicting the number of wins a team would achieve.
Here is the write up of the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-01-test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-01-test-post/</guid>
      <description>Insert Lead paragraph here.
A augue nunc lacus auctor efficitur tempor placerat, dictum volutpat mi vitae viverra porta non sem, himenaeos senectus vivamus potenti cubilia sollicitudin. Curae cursus inceptos tincidunt magna mi nibh ad enim etiam, molestie eu quis primis hendrerit taciti phasellus. Feugiat ultricies dictumst iaculis potenti odio laoreet urna at, ultrices curae leo accumsan proin sem lobortis.
Heading 2 Sollicitudin ornare odio blandit aenean enim lacus accumsan elementum vestibulum porta mauris lorem, ullamcorper class fermentum sem hendrerit ante augue penatibus scelerisque felis leo proin,ad nascetur venenatis sodales dignissim viverra suspendisse turpis convallis condimentum sapien.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>