<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perspective on Jeff Cavanagh</title>
    <link>/perspective/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perspective on Jeff Cavanagh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/perspective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalities</title>
      <link>/perspective/personalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/personalities/</guid>
      <description>Strength does not come from winning. Your struggles develop your strengths. When you go through hardships and decide not to surrender, that is strength.
- Arnold Schwarzenegger
  For me life is about continuously being hungry. The meaning of life is not simply to exist, to survive, but to move ahead, to group, to achieve, to conquer.
- Arnold Schwarzenegger
  Impossible is just a big word thrown around by small men who find it easier to live in the world they’ve been given than to explore the power they have to change it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry</title>
      <link>/perspective/poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/poetry/</guid>
      <description>Nothing Gold Can Stay The Road Not Taken   Nothing Gold Can Stay  Nature’s first green is gold,
Her hardest hue to hold,
Her early leaf’s a flower;
But only so an hour.
Then leaf subsides to leaf.
So Eden sank to grief,
So dawn goes down to day.
Nothing gold can stay.
- Robert Frost
  The Road Not Taken  Two roads diverged in a yellow wood,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Excerpts</title>
      <link>/perspective/text-excerpts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/text-excerpts/</guid>
      <description>Just Mercy   Just Mercy  We are all broken by something. We have all hurt someone and have been hurt. We all share the condition of brokenness even if our brokenness is not equivalent…
…Thomas Merton said: We are bodies of broken bones. I guess I’d always known but never fully considered that being broken is what makes us human. We all have our reasons. Sometimes we’re fractured by the choices we make; sometimes we’re shattered by things we would never have chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movies</title>
      <link>/perspective/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Good Will Hunting Hitch Lion King The Replacements Rocky Balboa   Good Will Hunting  Real loss is only possible when you love something more than you love yourself.
- Sean Maguire
  You’ll have bad times, but it’ll always wake you up to the good stuff you weren’t paying attention to. - Sean Maguire
  Hitch  Never lie, steal, cheat, or drink. But if you must lie, lie in the arms of the one you love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual</title>
      <link>/perspective/spiritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/perspective/spiritual/</guid>
      <description>Nothing is more practical than finding God,
than falling in Love in a quite absolute, final way.
What you are in love with,
what seizes your imagination, will affect everything.
It will decide
what will get you out of bed in the morning,
what you do with your evenings,
how you spend your weekends,
what you read, whom you know,
what breaks your heart,
and what amazes you with joy and gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>